

# Felmerald Besario

FullStack Website Developer / SEO **Specialist** 

felmeraldb@gmail.com

+639362114460

Talisay City, Philippines

linkedin.com/in/felmeraldbesario in

A highly motivated Website Developer / WordPress Developer with proven experiences in both Front-End & Back-End Web Development, has a strong knowledge in setting up different types of Web Hosting for migration. And has also skills and ability in Search Engine Optimization.

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

# Website Developer & SEO Specialist 8streetGuesthouse

03/2015 - 03/2016

8-A Sanson Road, Lahug, Cebu City.

8streetguesthouse is a hostel business with motorbikes rental.

Build their websites and maintained the 8streetguesthouse, ceburentabike, boholguesthouse, boholrentabike, motorbike's website utilizing HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, Codelgniter, WordPress and Search Engine Optimization. and Setup their domain, hosting, emails provider in Godaddy.

Contact: Badana, Eric (Owner) – eabadana@gmail.com (Phone:+639255888863)

### Website Developer / Back-end Developer Goirishtours

03/2016 - 03/2017

As Fortuna Bakilid Mandaue City

Innoveia Outsourcing (Go Irish Tours), Irelands award winning vacation company.

Achievements/Tasks

- Build, coordinate with the team and maintained the Go Irish Tours, Medilist, Placemat Builder's website utilizing HTML, CSS, WordPress, Codelgniter Web Framework. And assisted in organizing website's content and Graphics Design.

Contact: Gian Kim Jose Isulat (Manager) – (Email: webmaster@stagit.ie)

# Website Developer / Front-End Devloper & SEO Specialist Little Ripple Marketing / Our Global Team

04/2019 - 12/2019

Globe Telecom, Cebu Business Park, Cebu City

Software & Digital Marketing Australian Company

- Achievements/Tasks
- Build Little Ripple Marketing Company Website From Scratch.
- Convert PSD Files to WordPress & Woocommerce Website & Mobile Responsive.
- Set Up Domain, Emails, SSL Certificate, Hosting For Migrations & Cloudflare CDN.
- SEMrush SEO Audit, SEO SITE CHECKUP SEO Audit, (ON PAGE & OFF PAGE SEO)
- Handle Page Speed Optimization by following the GTmetrix, Pingdom, Google Page Speed Insights, Cloudflare, Making Sure that the website will load faster

Contact: Lee Bowers (CEO, Business Development Manager) - lee@littleripplemarketing.com.au -Baumel Tandugon (Manager) - baumel@adap.com.au

#### CERTIFICATES

SEMrush Technical & SEO Toolkit (04/2019 - 04/2020)

SEMrush SEO Fundamental & Advance SEMrush User (08/2019 – 08/2020)

OPIc (Oral Proficiency Interview by computer) (03/2019 – 03/2021)

#### **EDUCATION**

**Bachelor of Science in Information Technology** Salazar College of Science and Institute of Technology

06/2012 - 03/2016

- Awards / Certificates
- Top 3 in Dean's List.
- Best Team in Online System Application.
- Dynamic Website Designer.
- Best In Computer Graphics.

#### SKILLS

WordPress, PHP, MySQL, Webhooks

Angular Js, Javascript, jQuery, Ajax

E-Commerce

Hosting, Migrations & Cloudflare CDN

CSS, HTML, Bootstrap, MD Bootstap, Materialize CSS Framework

Page Speed Optimization, Pingdom, GTmetrix, Google PageSpeed Insights

SEMrush, SEOSITECHECKUP

Adobe Photoshop, Figma

Web Design

# VOLUNTEER EXPERIENCE

Full-Time Missionary The Church Of Jesus Christ Of Latter Day Saints

03/2017 - 03/2019

- Tasks/Achievements
- A Voluntary Desire to Preach the Gospel of Jesus Christ.
- Become Trainer, District & Zone Leader.
- Become a Mission Recoder & Referral Manager, and built Pcdom Web Offline System (Localhost) that can generates weekly, monthly reports to excell and Pdf Files using Codelgniter Web Framework and Bootstrap.

#### LANGUAGES

English, Cebuano and Tagalog











#### INTERESTS

Volunteer Work

Reading Scriptures

Googles in Website Technology & Design

Traveling, Fishing.

Basketball